<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Ramesh Srinivas</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Ramesh Srinivas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best technology decisions come from leaders who understand the terrain because they&amp;rsquo;re still walking it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;quote-author&#34;&gt;— Me, apparently&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Technology Initiative Pipeline: A Blueprint for AI-Augmented Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-development-blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-development-blueprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After decades of building software, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that the difference between projects that ship smoothly and projects that spiral isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; talent or technology — it&amp;rsquo;s process. And with AI now capable of being a genuine development partner, having the right process matters more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the blueprint I use at OptionsPlay to take initiatives from idea to production using AI-augmented development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure twice, cut once.&lt;/strong&gt; The quality of the output is directly proportional to the quality of the planning. Four stages of thinking, two of building. By the time you pick up the hammer, you already know where every nail goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From 22 Person-Weeks to 7 Days: What AI Pair Programming Actually Looks Like</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-pair-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-pair-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last August, I wrote an executive summary for a major platform initiative. I spec&amp;rsquo;d it out carefully: 10 weeks to production, 2-3 developers plus QA and BA support, roughly 22 person-weeks of effort. I&amp;rsquo;d been doing this long enough to know those were honest numbers — if anything, conservative for the scope.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six months later, I shipped it. Five working days. Just me and an AI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not a proof of concept. Not a prototype. A real-time rules engine evaluating thousands of securities every minute, generating ranked strategy recommendations across 11 strategy types, with an admin portal, 560 automated tests, and zero existing tests broken — integrated into a mature enterprise codebase with 100+ projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
