<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Ramesh Srinivas</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Ramesh Srinivas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Humans Are Not Machines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/humans-are-not-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/humans-are-not-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work with AI every day. It helps me write code, think through architecture, and move faster than I ever could alone. I&amp;rsquo;m the first to admit — when it comes to raw efficiency, I don&amp;rsquo;t stand a chance against the tools I use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And yet, I keep seeing a notion float around that troubles me: that humans are essentially machines, and machines are becoming essentially human. That the line between us is blurring to the point of irrelevance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Technology Initiative Pipeline: A Blueprint for AI-Augmented Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-development-blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-development-blueprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After decades of building software, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that the difference between projects that ship smoothly and projects that spiral isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; talent or technology — it&amp;rsquo;s process. And with AI now capable of being a genuine development partner, having the right process matters more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the blueprint I use at OptionsPlay to take initiatives from idea to production using AI-augmented development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure twice, cut once.&lt;/strong&gt; The quality of the output is directly proportional to the quality of the planning. Four stages of thinking, two of building. By the time you pick up the hammer, you already know where every nail goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From 22 Person-Weeks to 7 Days: What AI Pair Programming Actually Looks Like</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-pair-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ai-pair-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last August, I wrote an executive summary for a major platform initiative. I spec&amp;rsquo;d it out carefully: 10 weeks to production, 2-3 developers plus QA and BA support, roughly 22 person-weeks of effort. I&amp;rsquo;d been doing this long enough to know those were honest numbers — if anything, conservative for the scope.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six months later, I shipped it. Five working days. Just me and an AI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not a proof of concept. Not a prototype. A real-time rules engine evaluating thousands of securities every minute, generating ranked strategy recommendations across 11 strategy types, with an admin portal, 560 automated tests, and zero existing tests broken — integrated into a mature enterprise codebase with 100+ projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simply Grand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/grand-central/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/grand-central/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best technology decisions come from leaders who understand the terrain because they&amp;rsquo;re still walking it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;quote-author&#34;&gt;— Me, apparently&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Life Lessons from Teaching Tennis to My Kids</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tennis-life-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tennis-life-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Want to get good at something? Teach it.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve had to learn the intricate details of almost everything I do on the court, just so I can pass that knowledge to my kids. In the process, I&amp;rsquo;ve become a much better player than I ever was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Success — and failure — begins in the mind.&lt;/strong&gt; Henry Ford said, &amp;ldquo;Whether you think you can or think you cannot, you&amp;rsquo;re right.&amp;rdquo; For years, Roger Federer ruled men&amp;rsquo;s tennis. He stepped onto the court supreme in his belief that he could beat anyone. On the other side of the net, most opponents believed they had no shot — and the results followed. Then a precocious 22-year-old named Novak Djokovic declared he could take down the king. He lost that match in straight sets. But not long after, Novak proved he can beat anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let the Old Man In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/getting-older/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/getting-older/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My body isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly raring to go when getting out of bed these days. There&amp;rsquo;s an awareness of the physical body being past its prime. The person that stares back at me in the mirror seems much older than the mental image in my head.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking at the struggles my parents face daily, I&amp;rsquo;m aware of what&amp;rsquo;s coming. I did a lot of thinking when I was moving them to a retirement home a few weeks ago. The helplessness gnaws at me. It scares me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find the Artist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/find-the-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/find-the-artist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a meditation session, I see a photograph on my wall that I don&amp;rsquo;t recognize. It&amp;rsquo;s stunning — the composition is exquisite, the lighting is perfect, the subject couldn&amp;rsquo;t be better. I&amp;rsquo;m mesmerized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so gorgeous that I need to find the artist. I ask the people around me if they recognize it. I describe the photograph, the style, the mastery behind it. No one can place it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I keep looking. Eventually, someone thinks she might know, and gives me a location. I take a cab across the city and get there — but the guy at the desk tells me I have the wrong address. The artist might be at another location, across the water. I&amp;rsquo;d need to take a ferry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Things I&#39;ve Learned Being on Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/31-things-from-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/31-things-from-startups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my 22-year career as a technologist, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to be part of several startups. Some didn&amp;rsquo;t get off the ground. Some flattered to deceive. Others managed to get further along and become successful enough to be bought out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite a less than stellar success rate in general, and the significant risks associated with startups, I&amp;rsquo;ve always gravitated towards them. Why, you ask?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The success rate, the risks, the ups and downs notwithstanding — you can count on coming out at the other end with precious career and life lessons. You&amp;rsquo;re afforded the luxury and freedom to mold culture, to be creative, to innovate. Something that isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly easy to do at conventional organizations, even if you are an intrapreneur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
